<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>imagination on Process Imagining</title>
    <link>https://www.processimagining.com/tags/imagination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in imagination on Process Imagining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.processimagining.com/tags/imagination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>quote, catherine keller, on the mystery, 17.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-catherine-keller-on-the-mystery-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-catherine-keller-on-the-mystery-17/</guid>
      <description>Anselm classically defined theology as fides quarens intellectum&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;faith seeking understanding.&amp;rdquo; Not faith that already understands and so no longer needs to seek. That would by definition no longer be theology. Theology is not itself the faith but its quest. If we stop seeking, we are no longer on the way. Faith seeking understanding has then turned into &amp;ldquo;belief that understands.&amp;rdquo; It then closes the very root of quarens, from which come both question and quest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paul s. fiddes, freedom and limitation, 8.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/paul-s_w/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/paul-s_w/</guid>
      <description> the quest for a New World in literature would be mere escapism if we did not feel that the text was reaching out beyond itself to something of &amp;lsquo;ultimate concern&amp;rsquo; to us. It would be mere fantasy if we did not sense that it was pointing to a mysterious reality which can only be hinted at.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bell hooks, teaching critical thinking, 60.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/bell-hooks-teaching-critical-thinking-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/bell-hooks-teaching-critical-thinking-60/</guid>
      <description> In dominator culture the killing off of the imagination serves as a way to repress and contain everyone within the limits of the status quo.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/</guid>
      <description>Link to Aaron Cheak&amp;rsquo;s article is here.
I would like to thank Aaron Cheak for this wonderful translation from Henry Corbin. The selections get to the heart of Corbin&amp;rsquo;s understanding of alchemy. It resonates with the process of concrescence in Alfred North Whitehead. It breaks from any materialism and from any spiritualism. It seeks what Roland Faber writes as the intermezzo, the in-between. It is wholistic, in each different, with resonances when we relate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jean-luc nancy, the ground of image, 16-17.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/jean-luc-nancy-the-ground-of-image-16-17_hocpxol6igtdblvf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/jean-luc-nancy-the-ground-of-image-16-17_hocpxol6igtdblvf/</guid>
      <description>violence does not participate in any order of reasons&amp;hellip;it denatures, wrecks, massacres that which it assaults&amp;hellip;it is not the stupidity that comes from a lack of intelligence, but much worse: it is the stupidity of le con. It is the calculated absence of thought willed by rigid intelligence.
 In the moments of peaceful protest due to the murder of George Floyd, among the many more African Americans that have died due to police violence, I reflect on the above quote as poignant and reveals to us the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a selection from henry corbin&#39;s the jasmine of fedeli d&#39;amore</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore/</guid>
      <description>I am in the middle of writing my chapter on Imagination and the space of multiplicity, when I found this wonderful piece of translation and interpretation by Corbin, and had to add it here for rememberance. Here it goes:
&amp;ldquo;Seek Me in the Mystical Abode of Love &amp;quot; But, whoever dares to carry out this search will find himself obliged to defy the norms and forms of thought in the common, socialized forms of religion, and his proposals will sound like paradoxes (the shath of which Ruzbehan was so fond).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>beyond the bifurcation of imagination</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/beyond-the-bifurcation-of-imagination/</guid>
      <description>Reading Amy Kind and Peter Kung&amp;rsquo;s magnificent edited work Knowledge Through Imagination, and am thinking through it&amp;rsquo;s implications. For Kind/Kung, their goal in the text is to lift up the instructive implications of the imagination over and beyond the transcendent capabilities.
The problem with the transcendent capabilities of the imagination is its ability to disengage with the limitations of this worldly experience. That is, there are no constraints in the transcendent imagination (fantasy).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
