<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Process Imagining</title>
    <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Process Imagining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:11:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.processimagining.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>quote, alfred north whitehead, science and philosophy, p. 54.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/independentexistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:11:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/independentexistence/</guid>
      <description> The misconception which has haunted philosophic literature throughout the centuries is the notion of &amp;lsquo;independent existence.&amp;rsquo; There is no such mode of existence; every entity is to be understood in terms of the way it is interwoven with the rest of the universe.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>frithjof schuon, understanding islam, 139.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/frithjof-schuon-understanding-islam-139/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/frithjof-schuon-understanding-islam-139/</guid>
      <description> If the purest esoterism comprises total truth&amp;ndash;and that is the reason for its existence&amp;ndash;the question of &amp;ldquo;orthodoxy&amp;rdquo; in the religious sense quite obviously cannot arise; direct knowledge of the mysteries could not be &amp;ldquo;Muslim&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Christian&amp;rdquo;, just as the sight of a mountain and not something else.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote, catherine keller, on the mystery, 17.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-catherine-keller-on-the-mystery-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-catherine-keller-on-the-mystery-17/</guid>
      <description>Anselm classically defined theology as fides quarens intellectum&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;faith seeking understanding.&amp;rdquo; Not faith that already understands and so no longer needs to seek. That would by definition no longer be theology. Theology is not itself the faith but its quest. If we stop seeking, we are no longer on the way. Faith seeking understanding has then turned into &amp;ldquo;belief that understands.&amp;rdquo; It then closes the very root of quarens, from which come both question and quest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paul s. fiddes, freedom and limitation, 8.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/paul-s_w/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/paul-s_w/</guid>
      <description> the quest for a New World in literature would be mere escapism if we did not feel that the text was reaching out beyond itself to something of &amp;lsquo;ultimate concern&amp;rsquo; to us. It would be mere fantasy if we did not sense that it was pointing to a mysterious reality which can only be hinted at.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote, alan watts.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-alan-watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-alan-watts/</guid>
      <description>Advice? I don’t have advice. Stop aspiring and start writing. If you’re writing, you’re a writer. Write like you’re a goddamn death row inmate and the governor is out of the country and there’s no chance for a pardon. Write like you’re clinging to the edge of a cliff, white knuckles, on your last breath, and you’ve got just one last thing to say, like you’re a bird flying over us and you can see everything, and please, for God’s sake, tell us something that will save us from ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bell hooks, teaching critical thinking, 60.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/bell-hooks-teaching-critical-thinking-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/bell-hooks-teaching-critical-thinking-60/</guid>
      <description> In dominator culture the killing off of the imagination serves as a way to repress and contain everyone within the limits of the status quo.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alchemy as hieratic art, henry corbin</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alchemy-as-hieratic-art-henry-corbin_ue9ork487eecchjz/</guid>
      <description>Link to Aaron Cheak&amp;rsquo;s article is here.
I would like to thank Aaron Cheak for this wonderful translation from Henry Corbin. The selections get to the heart of Corbin&amp;rsquo;s understanding of alchemy. It resonates with the process of concrescence in Alfred North Whitehead. It breaks from any materialism and from any spiritualism. It seeks what Roland Faber writes as the intermezzo, the in-between. It is wholistic, in each different, with resonances when we relate with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/my-thoughts_37ogi01phezi2j96/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/my-thoughts_37ogi01phezi2j96/</guid>
      <description> The Image consumes us, but the imagination digests the image in order that we may do something with it. It moves us from vision to creativity.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote, roland faber, whitehead and the future of education</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-roland-faber-whitehead-and-the-future-of-educaiton_b1bqccscx7416ugc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-roland-faber-whitehead-and-the-future-of-educaiton_b1bqccscx7416ugc/</guid>
      <description> Measurement, I insist, is the death of education.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote, from a course i gave in eco-theology.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-from-a-course-i-gave-in-eco-theology_mdctqrvzj30krals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/quote-from-a-course-i-gave-in-eco-theology_mdctqrvzj30krals/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Appetition can also mean construction, the process of prehending a datum for feeling, taking things in, digesting. The reason for this is that to construct something one needs materials and to build what is being expressed. It is more than a postmodern shifting of objects and makes something new; we digest it in our senses, our mind does something with it, we construct.&amp;rdquo;
 I was trying to describe Alfred North Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s term &amp;ldquo;Appetition&amp;rdquo; and how it resonates with George Steiner&amp;rsquo;s understanding of Digestion vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jean-luc nancy, the ground of image, 16-17.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/jean-luc-nancy-the-ground-of-image-16-17_hocpxol6igtdblvf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/jean-luc-nancy-the-ground-of-image-16-17_hocpxol6igtdblvf/</guid>
      <description>violence does not participate in any order of reasons&amp;hellip;it denatures, wrecks, massacres that which it assaults&amp;hellip;it is not the stupidity that comes from a lack of intelligence, but much worse: it is the stupidity of le con. It is the calculated absence of thought willed by rigid intelligence.
 In the moments of peaceful protest due to the murder of George Floyd, among the many more African Americans that have died due to police violence, I reflect on the above quote as poignant and reveals to us the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alfred north whitehead, education and self-education.</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alfred-north-whitehead-education-and-self-education_hx8k4l74pjfclwvv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/alfred-north-whitehead-education-and-self-education_hx8k4l74pjfclwvv/</guid>
      <description> This cry for freedom seems at times to sleep for ages, like the fire in a volcano. When it wakes, the day of God&amp;rsquo;s judgment has arrived, and the worth of human societies is being weighted in His scales. Those societies perish which exhibit mainly selfishness and cowardice. Courage and hope are your best armour with which to meet a revolution&amp;ndash;and, above all, mutual sympathy.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a selection from henry corbin&#39;s _the jasmine of fedeli d&#39;amore_</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/a-selection-from-henry-corbins-the-jasmine-of-fedeli-damore/</guid>
      <description>I am in the middle of writing my chapter on Imagination and the space of multiplicity, when I found this wonderful piece of translation and interpretation by Corbin, and had to add it here for rememberance. Here it goes:
&amp;ldquo;Seek Me in the Mystical Abode of Love &amp;quot; But, whoever dares to carry out this search will find himself obliged to defy the norms and forms of thought in the common, socialized forms of religion, and his proposals will sound like paradoxes (the shath of which Ruzbehan was so fond).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combining process, postmodernism, and poststructuralism in imagination (work in progress)</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/combining-process-postmodernism-and-poststructuralism-in-imagination-work-in-pro_xga68mc3mlix4odo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/combining-process-postmodernism-and-poststructuralism-in-imagination-work-in-pro_xga68mc3mlix4odo/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t written a blog post in a bit, and wanted to at least throw out there what I am studying on, writing on.
Currently, I am reading Derrida, mainly two texts, The Insistence of God by Caputo, and Derrida and Theology by Shakespeare. They have been fascinating so far. I am amazed at the dillemma’s that Derrida is writing on, what he is trying to achieve, and how theologians are using it in their own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>truth, religion, process</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/truth-religion-and-process_64wnosmwvzofj50t/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/truth-religion-and-process_64wnosmwvzofj50t/</guid>
      <description>One of my main interests throughout my education has been trying to answer the question, “What is truth? What is ultimately true?” Now any reader may brush this off as not important, since we live in a postmodern/postcolonial world, but I would argue against that for various reasons. For simplicity I will hold to religion as my focal point; However, this can be used in any area: science, anthropology, sociology. All of these fields as well as many others can take hold of a primary position, making everything else subservient to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 axioms of alfred north whitehead&#39;s speculative philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/5-axioms-of-alfred-north-whiteheads-speculative-philosophy_s5dts89tdtsqn21p/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/5-axioms-of-alfred-north-whiteheads-speculative-philosophy_s5dts89tdtsqn21p/</guid>
      <description>In describing his Speculative Philosophy, Alfred North Whitehead shapes two categories; a rational side and empirical side. The rational is that of analysis: the empirical, that of value, importance.
The rational side in his metaphysics, or speculative philosophy, is found in the terms coherence and logic (consistency), “a coherent, logical, necessary system of general ideas in terms of which every element of our experience can be interpreted.” Working with Michel Weber&amp;rsquo;s text, Whitehead&amp;rsquo;s Pancreativism: The Basics, I hope to better understand what Whitehead is trying to do in his formation of Speculative Philosophy of Process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>god in the making</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/god-in-the-making_qspsle8yjf3bfo7b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/god-in-the-making_qspsle8yjf3bfo7b/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Roland Faber’s article titled ”God in the Making,” from the journal Aletheia is by far one of the best accounts of understanding Whitehead’s work in describing God on the basis of religious experience. I will try and do it some justice in this writing, but I would highly suggest you read it and come up with some creative responses.
My interest in particular is how one is able to see the ubiquitousness of religion, to say that they one can be christian, and at another moment in the event of experiencing an Sikh service, they one can also say ”I am a sikh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>horizontal-izing the vertical, eradicating the extremes: scales of value</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/horizontal-izing-the-vertical-eradicating-the-extremes-scales-of-value_0wypotx218oicl8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/horizontal-izing-the-vertical-eradicating-the-extremes-scales-of-value_0wypotx218oicl8c/</guid>
      <description>When we think we think in bifurcations. Up/down. Left/right. Right/wrong. This way of thinking causes either/or mentality. It indicates that one is right, and the other is wrong.
But what would happen if we flatten it out? We make what is vertical thinking horizontal? What if we said that in order to have one, you need the other? That it is relationally intertwined so that if one does not exist, the other does not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nomadology: deleuze, the state and the war machine</title>
      <link>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/nomadology-deleuze-the-state-and-the-war-machine_gqhbq5zm2ep2kmjr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.processimagining.com/posts/nomadology-deleuze-the-state-and-the-war-machine_gqhbq5zm2ep2kmjr/</guid>
      <description>In an essay entitled “Treatise on Nomadology—The War Machine” in A Thousand Plateaus, Gilles Deleuze’ critiques the notion of the state by not its opposite, but rather exterior from it; he develops the concept of the nomad/war machine. I call it exterior from the State, because its opposite can still exist within it. He wants to break from the transcendental nature of the State by deriving a set of principles rather than a framework to lift up difference rather than unification by assimilation and classification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
